hi folks I'm Shashank I work with ditto
insurance we are an insurance advisory
platform where we deal with health and
term insurance plans now if you're out
here looking for Quality advice then we
recommend you to book a free of cost
consultation with our advisers with the
link in the description with the
introduction out of the way folks let me
now introduce Our Guest today suant he
is the senior program manager here at
ditto and today we are going to talk
about adya beras on life insurance suant
welcome to the podcast thanks for having
me so suant let's start with the
introduction and the basic metrics how
they're operating so take us through the
details um so they actually do have
quite an interesting story um adla
sunlife was established in the year 2000
um and it's actually joint venture
between adla capital and Sun Life
Insurance Incorporated from Canada so
yeah and I think over the last 202 5
years they've really established
themselves by offering a very
Diversified portfolio of plans right
ranging from term insurance to ulips to
endowments um even child plans and
retirement plans as well so I think
they've really tried to cater to pretty
much all the sort of sectors of the
audience all right all right and uh how
are they operationally uh I think if I
were to talk about their metrics first
if we look at claim settlement ratio for
example um quite good in the recent
years their average has been just over
98% uh which is well above the industry
average and and a really good number if
I were to talk about amount settlement
ratio pretty solid on that front too
about 94% change which is pretty good um
coming to the complaints volume very
reasonable for every 10,000 claims
they've had just five complaints once
again that's well below the industry
average um and in terms of annual
business they've been growing steadily
year on year so we're looking at about
6,500 crores of annual business per year
okay pretty solid uh metrics over there
now let's talk about their offerings in
terms of term plans um so they have
about three term plans if I were to pick
the flagship one which is called Digi
Shield um under that is's about 10
variants or options that you can play
around with so one would be a return of
Premium variant where you get your money
back at the end of the plan one would be
a whole life cover where you're allowed
to be insured for the entirety of your
life meaning until 99 or 100 years of
age if I were to talk about the age of
entry for this plan it's about 18 to 65
um for some insur you're allowed to buy
minimum of 30 lakhs and there's no upper
limit which is quite interesting right
most companies set a cap that you can't
buy more than 10 20 30 crores here there
is no cap of course subject to your
eligibility and underwriting in terms of
riders and optional benefits that they
offer there are some interesting
features there too they have an
accidental death and disability benefit
wherein for an accidental death you paid
a higher sum in short um for an accident
disability you paid a percentage of the
rider based on the disability that
happens and this is all clearly listed
out all right they have a criticalness
variant even there they have two options
so one is a Critic critical illness
accelerated variant covering about 42
illnesses um and then there's a normal
criticalness variant covering just four
critical illnesses so I feel there maybe
they probably are lacking a little bit
whereas other brands offer the 20 30 40
illnesses that's right um so that's
probably one place where I would say
they're slightly lacking okay they also
off another free benefit called The Life
Stage benefit where you're allowed to
increase your Su insured up to 100% in
the future based on certain life stages
like marriage and having kids this plan
also comes with an inbuilt terminal
illness benefit in case someone's
terminally ill they can claim an
accelerated amount of their term
insurance um lastly they have some
unique features such as a surgical care
Rider meaning in case you require a
surgery of some sorts uh diagnosed and
approved by a medical professional they
will pay up a certain amount that to
financially support you and they also
have a hospit care benefit which very
few insurance companies offer which is
more of a health insurance benefit if
you ask me but how this feature works is
ke once you're admitted to the hospital
if you're there for more than 2 or 3
days they give you a certain day daily
cash allowance daily cash is what we
call it in health insurance terms but
corre in term insurance they call it the
hospit care benefit so you're given a
daily allowance every day to kind of
help you with miscellaneous expenses um
but yeah I think that more or less
summarizes the digi Shield plan Digi
Shield is a really really comprehensive
plan now I have also gone through the
brochure and they also have something
called as an income suraka plan right uh
some more details on that this actually
is a very interesting take on term
insurance right they've really
approached it from a different angle all
together okay um so even under this
there are two variants one is called the
uh fixed income plan wherein they focus
on giving your nominees the death
benefit in the form of monthly income so
how they've done it is that you get to
choose what amount you want your
nominees to receive for example you say
that I want them to receive 1 lakh
rupees per month in case something ought
to happen to me um they offer this for a
fixed tenure of 10 years or the
remaining of the policy tenure whichever
is higher so if I were to give you an
example let's say I buy a term insurance
for 30 years and the person or the
insured member passes away in the 15th
year now his family will receive 1 lakh
per month for the next 15 years because
that was the remaining of the policy
tenure okay this is one example so the
other one is the increasing income
protection variant that they have here
how it works is whatever income you've
decided that your family should receive
that amount will keep increasing by 5%
Year onye from the date you've bought
the plan the tenure here Remains the
Same the payout tenure is 120 months or
10 years basically so meaning if someone
has bought a plan and 5 years later he
were to pass away now initially when he
bought the plan he opted for 1 lakh
rupees as monthly income but in those 5
years this has been compounding so now 5
years later when something happens his
family is eligible to receive 1.21 lakhs
or so approximately per month okay and
this will still keep increasing as it's
paid out until it reaches an upper cap
of about 1.5 lakh rupees so basically
1.5 times of the income you asked for
should you have asked for 2 lakhs it
will grow until it reaches 3 lakhs 1.5x
ENT enally understood quite interesting
variance right I think something unheard
of altogether in term insurance true but
if you were to ask me and we' even
consulted with a few Financial experts
um they're also of the opinion that look
maybe this variant isn't the most
helpful or beneficial um and like I said
I'm of the same opinion as well right I
believe a term insurance or life
insurance should have a lumpsum payout
to the nominees or family members
exactly reason being this gives them the
flexibility to do what they want with
the money you're not leaving it with
someone and saying that look I'm happy
with the lack of month I'd rather the
family gets the one or two crores and
one if they have any major debts they
can clear them off they have some big
expenses coming up it might support them
or two at least they can open something
as simple as an FD and kind of generate
6 7% interest every year right so you
have a steady flow of income while you
also have that Corpus L as a security in
the bank makes sense so from a financial
standpoint I would still always go for a
lumpsum option but I think just how
interesting and unique these were I
think definitely worth discussing
definitely definitely worth mention uh
uh now we've covered both these plans uh
let's quickly go into the third plan um
so the last variant is called the salary
term plan as the name suggests is
something that's specifically for
salaried individuals only um it comes
with some unique benefits but innovates
also similar to their Digi Shield plan
okay let's say in terms of the age of
Entry firstly right 18 to 65 is the
maximum age of Entry the duration
they've allowed a maximum tenure of up
to 70 years that's the capping they've
set um in terms of the cover amount 25
lakhs is the bare minimum you can choose
um and there's no upper limit of course
subject to underwriting and your
financial eligibility it comes with the
Free Rider of terminal benefit so that's
an added Advantage as well pricing I
think is where they really stand out
right they've they've really designed
this in such a way that uh they offer
some additional discounts for salaried
individuals and also on the basis of
gender okay like we've seen before in
term insurance for females the prices
can be lower right considering a higher
mortality rate and longer life
expectancy so these are some of the
broad sort of overview if I had to cover
them in terms of specific pricing though
if I had to talk about some numbers for
a 25-year-old male buying a 1 CR term
plan um the salary term plan would cost
about 9,500 or so per year the digi
Shield plan would cost about 11,000
change um and the income plan that we
spoke about that would be somewhere
around 25 26,000 okay um per year for an
income of about 50,000 Rupees per month
should something happen um so this is
what you can see from the pricing that
yes this one is priced quite
comparatively right even compared to the
digi Shield plan correct and in case if
I were to increase the age of the
individual to 35 from 25 uh what was
9,000 change would now become 14,000 um
the digi Shield which used to be 11
would be about 15 16 um and the income
plan which is about 25,000 earlier is
now looking at about 28 29,000 so more
or less of proportion increase nothing
significant sort of stands out here all
right uh so now in terms of of uh the
recommendations that we have at you know
Max life htfc life so how are the
premiums priced based on that so once
again let me give it to you with an
example of the same profile a 25y old 1
CR plan till
65 um the digi Shield plan was about
11,5 600 um the salary term plan was
about 9,500 or so this is The Benchmark
we've set for AAA coming to Max life
they're reasonably priced quite close
somewhere about 10,100 a year
um icac is a bit higher at about
10,900 and HDFC is even more expensive
than the digi Shield plan they're about
11,900 so I think yeah this is what it
would compare and like you can see
they're quite competitive nothing really
stands out or no added Advantage either
okay um so they're offering similar
prices but they're also you know
competing with some of the largest
players out there in the industry all
right so finally what's the final word
on um adya Bas and life insurance so I
think based on analysis they really do
stand out as a solid player right um
like we just looked at in terms of
pricing as well they're able to compete
with some of the large players out there
um in terms of features they're quite
comprehensive they offer the accident
plans their waiver of premium coverage
critical illness all the benefits right
that are gely available out there coming
to the operational metrics like we saw
complaint volume as well was quite low
in fact lower than even some of these
brands at about five complaints every
10,000 right um so honestly from that
front no no complaints or no issues as
such uh the only thing I would say is
that yes there're a smaller play player
when compared to the top three or top
five out there um so that's something
that's up to user right whether he
wishes to take that risk or would he
want more peace of mind going with one
of the larger established players out
there understood uh but other than that
nothing against them they really are a
good option available that's great
that's a that's a good insight suan and
thank you so much uh for for going into
detail of uh ad Bas and life insurance
now folks if you enjoyed the video don't
forget to drop a like And subscribe if
you haven't already
and if you have any doubts uh please put
them in the comments below and we will
see you in the next one until then Happy
Insurance hunting